Ashwani Kumar RajputPremium CV Featured Resume

Senior Web Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSP, Servlets, Bootstrap, AJAX, JSON, React

Current Designation: Senior Web Developer

Current Company: AKQA Media India Pvt. Ltd.,

Current Location: Gurgaon

Pref. Location: Delhi, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computer Science and Engineering]

Key Skills: Senior Web Developer, Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSP, Servlets, Bootstrap, AJAX, JSON, React

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 04a3bcbf1231f98382Last Active: Jul-Sep 2020Last Modified: Jul-Sep 2020

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Senior web developer with 9.8 years of experience in UI. Specializes in HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Vanilla JavaScript, Object Oriented JS, React and Responsive Design. Leveraging JavaScript to build responsive websites and interactive features that drive business growth and improve UX.

Work Experience

AKQA Media India Pvt. Ltd., as Senior Web Developer

May 2017 to Till Date

Analyzed requirements and designs, developed responsive e-commerce web applications components from scratch

Designed and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement

Developed UI for trebble web applications and IWC watch configurator using React and bootstrap 4

Developed UI for Online Customer Service Tracking System from scratch which is being used by IWC.com and Panerai.com

Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser & devices compatibility

Leading a team of size 12 people of UI only for delivering the end to end solutions with assuring the code quality and web accessibility.

Datamatics Global Services Limited as Senior Interactive Developer

Dec 2015 to Apr 2017

Analyzed requirements and designs, developed responsive e-commerce web applications components from scratch for DOVE and AXE

Highly focused on code quality and web performance issues to reduce UI non-responsiveness by 70%

Fareportal as Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2015 to Nov 2015

Developed Explore Tool from scratch in Spring, JSP, JDBC, Web Services, Ember JS and Bootstrap with usage of High Chart APIs and Google Map APIs

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU) in 2010

PG: M.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering) from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi in 2016

^ Back to Top IT Skills Skill Name Version Last Used Experience **REACT** JavaScript **JQUERY** AJAX AND JSON CSS **BOOTSTRAP** HTML5 and CSS3 JSP, SERVLETS ^ Back to Top Languages Known Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

English